There's no need for
you to play peacemaker.
Your mother and I
got it all worked out.
Hey. Sergeant.
Hmm?
I just want to thank you
for this opportunity.
I'm gonna do
a great job.
Fine.
Do you wanna keep
answering phones?
I wanna be a Chicago
Police officer.
Let's do it then.
So. Lexi. you have a
college picked out yet?
Actually. I was thinking
about riding around
with my boyfriend's
band for a while.
They're doing this tour
from Chicago to Portland.
What does he play?
Whoa. This is
the first time I'm
hearing about this.
No. it's not.
I told you about it. like.
two weeks ago. Remember?
Erin. how old were you
when you first decided
to be the police?
Well. it was right
after Hank took me in.
I was fifteen.
You go to college
to be a cop?
No. I barely made it
through high school.
Look. I spent four years on
the West side in a patrol car.
that was my education.
So life experience is just
as important as school.
No. No. I mean. if
I had to do it again
I would definitely get
a degree. But. I...
Look. I gotta get to class.
But it was good
seeing you. Erin.
Yeah. you too. kid.
Bye. Dad.
See you. baby.
See you.
All right.
Bye.
I'll see you later.
Alvin. I hate to break it
to you. but I don't think
Lexi is interested
in being a cop.
She wants to be a roadie
with her boyfriend's band.
Yeah. she's a kid.
I gotta go check
this guy out.
No. Alvin. no. Don't.
I'll do it.
Be advised. any tac
units in the vicinity
of Cermak and Archer.
a patrol officer is requesting
the closest unit with
breaching tools to respond.
It's two blocks away.
All right. what the hell?
Let's do our good
deed for the day.
You the one that called
for the breach?
Yeah. Com Ed guy was
replacing a meter
around back.
Called in a foul odor.
All right.
Ooh!
Whoa!
Whoa.
Yeah. Uh.
Yeah. that stinks
to high heaven.
Oh. my God!
Lincoln.
5021.
I have multiple
DOAs on scene.
Send the coroner
to 2122 West Cermak.
Copy that.
Al...
Al. we got to check
the rest of the building.
Hey. Excuse me.
Chicago Police.
Help me! Please!
It's okay.
It's all right. It's
all right. It's good.
Ma'am. you're going to be
okay. You're going to be okay.
Al. are you okay?
I'm fine. I'm fine.
Find the car yet?
No. they've issued
a city-wide manhunt.
All right. I'm gonna
get some tape.
We need to block
off the street.
Help me! My little girl!
She's been shot!
We were shopping
and she was hit.
It's a stray bullet
from the shooter.
She's lost a lot of blood.
her pulse is down
to below twenty.
This is unit
2113.
we're at the twenty-one
hundred block of Cermak.
Please roll another
ambulance to the scene.
Unit 21 13.
the closest available
ambo is ten minutes out.
I'm taking her in the squad.
Wait. wait. wait. you can't
transport an injured
victim in a patrol car.
Oh. please! Please!
Hey. you take that kid
and we could all be
looking at a lawsuit.
Out of my way. DeLuca.
Put that kid down!
If that girl dies we
can all lose our badges.
Follow me.
I said no.
You wanna help him up or
end up down there with him?
An autopsy isn't going to
solve any big mysteries here.
These girls died
from a combination of
starvation and dehydration.
Check this out.
Bruises to her face.
They fought each other
over the water.
Figured the shooter was here
to bring the girls food.
But he got here too late.
The ME says the girls
have been dead for
at least two days.
Anything on the
shooter's vehicle?
No. Only got
a partial plate.
Waiting to hear back.
Uh. landlord says he's
been getting paid
cashier's checks by a guy
a year in advance.
Well. the shooter ain't our
guy. I can tell you that much.
No businessman
is gonna leave his
investment for dead.
Please.
Whoa. Hey.
Whoa. hey. whoa. whoa.
whoa. No. no. no. Hey!
You don't understand.
Get back there.
Please.
Get back behind
the line. pal.
Hey. look at me. Get
back behind the line.
This is police stuff. You got
to get back. all right?
Hey. what's the problem?
He says his daughter
might be inside.
I need to make
sure. Please!
Sir. this is
a crime scene...
No. it's okay.
We got it. We got it.
Come on in.
My daughter.
That's her.
That's Jun.
Mr. Chen. we're so
sorry for your loss.
Please.
we're trying to help you.
Just tell us who you paid
to bring Jun over here.
And you're not gonna
get into any trouble.
No.
You know.
we just want to
know what happened.
Yeah.
I paid them 30.000
to bring Jun over.
I got a call last week
that she was in the city.
They wouldn't tell me where.
And they demanded
another thirty.
And I didn't have it.
Please. Just give
us a name.
Dennis Lee.
The Dennis Lee? Used
to run Chinatown?
Hey.
You know. I heard
that. uh. that
Chinatown was a
war zone this morning.
You know. I've been involved
in more than a few
skirmishes myself.
With the bullets
flying. there's...
There's got to be
a million things going
through your head.
Yeah.
it wasn't pretty.
Hey.
Can I have you to look
into somebody for me?
Consider it extra credit.
Yeah. sure. Who's the.
uh. who's the target?
Olinsky's
daughter's boyfriend.
All right.
I'll send you the details.
Dennis Lee.
He's been on CPD's
most-wanted fugitive
list for over six years.
He's wanted on more than
50 combined warrants.
including firearms
and human trafficking.
I ran across Lee back in Vice.
He made his fortune
supplying the South side
with the three G's. girls.
guns and gambling machines.
All three he brought over from
China in shipping containers.
So he thinks six years
is long enough for the heat
to die down. and now
he's back in business?
I got a hit on the
burgundy Toyota Supra.
It's registered to
this guy. Eddie Cao.
Dennis Lee's nephew.
That's him.
That's the shooter.
Well. when he's not running
errands for his uncle.
he's a known counterfeiter.
who does everything from
knock-off DVDS to Gucci bags.
Runs a sweatshop
down on Wentworth.
Gear up.
All right. Halstead.
Ruzek. Atwater.
you cover the exits.
Everybody stay sharp.
This guy won't
think twice about
lighting up cops.
You ready?
Hit it.
Police!
Wake up!
Eddie Cao.
Let me show you what
happens when you
shoot at the police.
So.
where's your uncle?
I don't know.
Where is he?
Where's Dennis Lee?
Where is Dennis Lee?
You. you got about two
seconds before he turns
your hand into a glove.
Okay! He gave me ten G's
to make the fake passports
and watch those girls!
And you left them in there
like dogs on chains to die.
huh. while you got high?
While you got high.
I don't know
where he crashes!
But my uncle's moving
a major load today.
Hey. look at me.
He's bringing in more girls?
No man. not girls. Guns.
All right.
Al.
Al?
Get this?
Yeah.
So.
we got a real
good news/bad news
situation here.
Give us the bad news first.
The good news is. the
gunshot victim you brought
over to Chicago Med.
she's gonna live.
They're gonna keep her
over for observation
but they're hopeful
she'll make
a full recovery.
So we made
the right call.
Which brings us
to the bad news.
Officer DeLuca.
he's at Chicago Med
too. getting an MRI.
Are you kidding me?
I just shoved the guy!
More bad news.
He filed a formal complaint.
What?
You're gonna
have to debrief
Commander Fischer.
and I would come up
with something better
than "I shoved him."
An MRI? You
believe that guy?
Sean. we did
what we had to do.
Fischer will understand that.
I don't know. The
more stripes they
have on their sleeve.
the less they
seem to understand.
Yeah.
That was Interpol.
they said Lee practically
started a war in Shanghai.
He stole money from
his business partners
and burned every contact
that was protecting him.
Eddie Cao said
his uncle is unloading
4.000 SKS assault
rifles at 500 apiece.
That's two mill.
No wonder Lee's back.
That's a huge payday.
Lee comes back to Chicago.
bringing with him
shipping containers full
of girls and guns.
Sells them all at once.
then hauls ass out of town.
Mouse and I were able
to ID another of the girls
from the warehouse luggage.
Her name is Mai Ling.
She was 14.
We're trying to track
down family for
the rest of the girls.
and I've reached out
to ICE to help with IDs.
Right. you know. the parents
are probably scared to talk.
Just stay on 'em.
No. his nephew said Lee's
gonna sell these rifles
in two hours at
the container yards.
That's the only way
we're gonna get him.
so what are we
waiting for?
All right. go with Al.
Set up surveillance.
How many years
Al got on the job?
25. 26.
He could've retired by now.
Moved to Florida.
Olinsky had full
pension five years ago.
I don't think getting fat and
tan in Orlando is his thing.
Any movement?
Negative. Al. Nothing yet.
After his nephew put on
that little fireworks
display this morning.
maybe Lee decided
to ditch the meet.
No. this guy doesn't
walk away from money.
You guys got eyes on this?
Yeah. Six Asian males.
Looks like our buyers.
I'm gonna run the plates.
see if I can.
uh. get an ID.
Don't bother.
I know that guy.
It's Jesse Kong.
Leader of the
Fourteen K Triads.
Let's take 'em.
Chicago Police!
Put your hands in the sky.
Put them up! Walk
back to the red car!
Keep it going.
Hands up!
Get your hands up!
Police!
Move over to the car!
Hands up!
Drop your bag.
Get on the ground.
Knees on the ground.
Over by the red car.
Put your hands on the truck.
Where's Lee?
Hey. hey! Where's Lee?
I don't know. I don't know.
Some Chinese
dude paid me a grand to
show up here with a key.
Give me the keys.
Which one is it?
It's the red one
over there.
Over by the red car.
Put your hands on the truck.
So Lee gave you
that container number?
Called me. Said to
meet him there.
Had heat on him
'cause of that junkie
nephew of his.
He wanted to unload
some guns quick-like.
We only counted
50K here. Jesse.
You think Lee was
really gonna sell you
4.000 SKSs at
that kinda discount?
All I know is Lee
set you up.
and set me up.
Guess we both got played.
I'll take my phone call now.
Lee never meant
to sell to the Triads.
After his nephew made
headlines this morning.
he picked up the
real container earlier.
The one we got was just
a decoy to keep us busy
while he's out selling
to the real buyers.
We find them. we find Lee.
All right. what about Kong?
He's asking for
his phone call.
Sergeant. we're all set.
I wired-up
Jesse Kong's vehicle.
I got two pin-hole
cameras. a mic. and GPS.
All right. beautiful. We're
gonna kick Jesse Kong
and the rest of his crew.
Whoa. whoa. whoa.
wait a sec. wait a sec.
We got the Triads in
conspiracy to purchase
weapons. Come on.
Al. they just got
burned by Dennis Lee.
We're about to use
that to our advantage.
You wanna make a call?
How about I make you
a one-time-only deal.
That is. if you're interested
in finding Dennis Lee.
I'm interested.
You find him before
we do. I wanna know.
I'll drop all charges.
I get a badge. too?
What you get
is twelve hours.
If you screw me.
I'll make sure the Gang
Unit puts you to bed
for the next year.
I guess my question is.
what street crew has the
bankroll to buy two million
dollars' worth of hardware?
Let's start running gang
files. I can reach
out to a few CIs.
Al.
you got some people
downstairs who
want to talk to you.
No. take a message.
Nah. I think you
wanna go down. man.
Detective Olinsky.
Yes?
They wanted to
come forward.
Their girls. they
were with Jun.
I'm sorry for your loss.
I know you're
doing everything you can.
And we wanted to
make sure you had these.
They belonged
to our daughters.
They are tokens of luck.
To help you
find the man who
took them from us.
Hey. are you
working somethin'?
Um. no.
No. I like to
watch the lights
come and go. I find
it kinda relaxing.
Interesting.
Hmm.
Did you run the kid?
Yeah. Uh.
it's. uh. Jason Monahan.
Guy has no arrest record.
His mom is a
physical therapist.
Dad teaches music
composition at
the Art Institute.
Jason posted some of
his music on. uh. on Vine.
He can beat the
hell out of a bass.
What kind of music?
Neo-Punk.
Yeah. not as good as the
Bad Brains or anything.
More like old Ramones.
Hmm.
I could track him
if you want.
Tag his tour van.
install a camera.
It's all right. I got
it from here. thank you.
Yeah.
Hey.
Sorry to bother
you this late.
Where is he?
Out back. tearing
apart the garage.
I didn't know
who else to call.
It's all right.
I'll talk to him.
Hey. uh.
things between me
and Al have been
really good lately.
But that look I saw
in his eye tonight.
I've seen that look
too many times before.
and every time I did
I lost him for months.
Okay.
Kinda little late to be
cleaning out the garage.
I only got one glass.
Al. what are you doing?
These are my file
from Organized Crime.
When the
unit was disbanded.
I don't know. uh.
I just couldn't
let everything go.
But Meredith just moved
everything around. so I...
And what's so important
you got to find at
two in the morning?
When we were
closing in on Lee
I spent a lot of time
in the wire room.
Listening to his calls.
there was one name that
just kept popping up.
A prostitute.
She was Lee's mistress.
He was
crazy about her.
So. now. if she's still
in Chinatown. I know.
I know he'd go
and see her.
And I know I wrote it down!
I know I wrote it down!
You know. those
girls' parents...
What am I
supposed to tell them
if I let this guy
slip away again?
Hey. I wanna nail
him as bad as you.
Look. I mean. come on.
I don't gotta tell you.
Sometimes they get away.
Six years ago. I lied
on that warrants
to search Lee's
shipping containers.
He was good and
had no real. hard intel
on him. The guy...
Nobody would
talk in Chinatown.
So what do you do. you
follow your gut. right?
Busted one open.
it had guns in it.
Another one had
poker machines. and...
Then brass finds out about my
thin paperwork.
and they get nervous.
they shut me down.
Two days later
the guy's in the wind.
So.
if. if I didn't screw up
and had arrested him then.
those girls
that we found today.
they wouldn't be
dead right now.
They wouldn't be.
Officer Roman.
Patrolman DeLuca
filed a formal
complaint against you
for aggravated battery.
I already heard
his side of the story.
So why don't you tell me
what happened out there?
We were attempting
to transport a
tender-aged child
to the hospital for
medical treatment.
And I had to remove
DeLuca from our path.
You were a witness to
this infraction. Yet
you failed to report.
Yeah. because there was
nothing to report. Commander.
I mean. we did
the right thing...
Burgess.
My partner isn't to
blame. Commander.
It was my decision
to move the victim.
As much as I admire
that. Patrolman.
you can't hit
another cop under
any circumstances.
Until further notice.
you're suspended.
I'll be calling my FOP rep.
That would be wise.
I got a name and
number I need you to run.
Oh. morning. Detective.
Hey.
Yeah. Anna Tse?
Um. Sergeant Voight
already notified me.
I'm already on it.
Now her number has
been out of service
for years. And there's
about a dozen Anna Tse's
in the Chicago area.
But. based on the fact
she was a prostitute.
I went ahead and checked
to see if any of them
have been arrested for
solicitation. and. uh. well.
this has gotta be her.
And check this out.
see. I figured that she'd
be. uh. she'd be managing
a massage parlor.
All right? No. no. no
she went and got her.
uh. her finance degree.
Yeah. she... She's a loan
manager over at the
Midwestern Trust.
Immigrant working
girl makes good.
It's the American Dream.
Give me her address.
Anna Tse. open up!
Do it.
Were you talking to Lee?
Do you have
a warrant for this?
Shut up.
Turn around.
Anna Tse. you're
under arrest
for aiding and
abetting a fugitive.
You've come a long way
since your days in the
massage parlor. Anna.
How nice of you
to remind me.
Well. what I don't get
is. why?
Why let him back
into your life?
It's what I don't get.
You could never understand.
Yeah? Well. right now
I'm looking to put six
homicides on you.
So. so you try me.
Hey.
The province
where I'm from.
complete and
total poverty.
I was 17 when Dennis
brought me over.
And if he hadn't...
He helped me find
a better life.
What about the victims?
Where's their better life?
Oh. I came here
just the same.
Small container
with a hole punched
on top for light.
And some of us die.
some of us win.
You tell me where he is.
Several calls were
made late last night
from your office phone
at Midwestern Trust
to a studio owned by
Reggie "Sticks" Daniels.
The head of the Vice Lords.
Is that who's
buying the guns?
Dennis doesn't tell
me his business.
Oh. The Vicelords are
looking to making
power-moves on the west side.
They need the hardware.
All right. grab the others.
Let's get vested up.
Hey.
We're gonna find Lee.
And he's gonna go away a
long time for what he let
happen to those girls.
You couldn't catch
him before.
What makes you think
you can catch him now?
I did it. CPD written exam.
95. Not bad.
What? What do you mean?
It's basically 100.
That's like saying the
Hawks basically beat
the Kings last night
even though they
lost by a goal.
Yeah. well. next
step. psych exam.
New policy. every
candidate has to
take a polygraph.
They grill you
about your past.
I don't know.
All the stuff I've done.
We'll see.
High five!
Hello. You've gotta
drop those charges
against Sean.
Not only did that prick
cheap shot me. he
chipped my tooth. Look.
I'm gonna have to have
cosmetic work done.
that's not covered
under CPD insurance.
You tell Roman
to cough up $3.000
and I'll consider
dropping the charges.
Until then.
my meatball sub's
getting cold.
Believe it or not.
some good artists
come out of here.
Not that anybody cares.
Take a break. darling. Now.
Um. excuse me. Wait!
Everybody. hands
in the air. now.
Oh. Hey. hey!
Chicago Police! Hands away
from the hardware!
Everybody on the ground!
Put 'em up! Which one
of you is Reggie? Huh?
I make music. man.
I ain't got no
interest in guns.
Some crates get
dumped at my studio.
first thing I'm thinking is.
must be the new sound
mixers I ordered.
Yeah. some mistake.
The Postal Service.
man. they always
messin' up.
Right.
See. I don't think
you're so stupid
that you don't realize
today is your lucky day.
We don't want you. Hey.
we want Dennis Lee.
'Cause while he
was selling you guns.
he let six teenage
girls rot to death.
Look. man. I'm telling you.
the only Chinese
dude I know is the
one that sells me
fried rice down
at the Golden Duck.
Sergeant.
What?
I got something
you wanna see.
Check it out. that
Triad vehicle you
had me wire-up...
Yeah.
We gotta hit on Lee.
He's crashin' at the
Royal Hotel on Michigan.
Spread the word.
When was this?
Two minutes ago.
Got the tracker up on
Kong's car. they're heading
to the hotel right now.
Get the long guns.
Everybody. get down!
Drop your weapons.
Put it down!
Jesse.
Al. go. I got you. Go!
Get out here.
Put your gun down!
Get on your knees.
Drop it!
Drop it! Drop it.
Put your gun down.
You forget about
our deal. Jesse?
I was gonna
bring you his head.
Dennis Lee. You're
under arrest.
Don't!
Come here.
Don't you even
look at me. man.
Get on the ground.
Detective Olinsky.
Organized Crime.
I never forget a face.
You should've never
come back here.
This ends for
you right now.
Whoa. whoa. whoa.
Al.
Get him out of here. now.
On your
feet. Let's go.
Al. we're good?
Yeah.
Yeah. you wanted
to see us?
Where's Anna?
Your true love?
She's in custody.
She's being shipped
down to 26th
and Cal as we speak.
Well. I guess
that's cleared up.
Let her go.
I'll sign whatever
confession you want.
Let me tell you something.
I'm not making any trades.
You let six girls die
just 'cause you got greedy.
What happened to
those young women.
I'm not proud.
But those parents.
they know the risks.
I think Anna knew
the risk when she got
in bed with you.
And what's more.
she's gonna do time
no matter what you sign.
And guess what.
when she gets out
she's gonna end up
just where she started.
Hustling johns for rent money.
And you.
you're gonna die in a cell
the size of this room.
I guess that's it then.
Crossing somebody off
the most wanted list
after six years.
That's gotta feel good.
Yeah.
So Mouse and I looked
into Lexi's boyfriend.
He's spotless.
She's lucky to have you
looking out for her.
Thanks.
Al. don't go crawling under
a rock after this. okay?
You gotta focus of all
the ones you saved.
getting Lee off the street.
She passed.
Couldn't make heads
or tails of this one.
You gonna have
to re-test her?
Do you know how
many new applicants
I got to do this week?
Seems like a nice
girl. Sure she'll
make fine police.
Or not. that's
not my department.
Okay. That friggin' hurt.
What are you
complaining about?
You passed.
I did?
I told you it would work.
If you can't beat the
machine. you wear it down.
Thank you.
Okay. Onto phase three.
the physical exam.
I'm gonna pull up some of
my old work-out plans.
You wouldn't believe what
I used to be able to squat.
Oh. sounds good.
You wanted to see me.
Sergeant Voight?
Yeah. come on in.
And close the door.
Have a seat.
The dentist from
my social club
does excellent work.
Bill's taken care of...
All due respect. sir.
I already worked all this
out with Officer Roman.
You think you're
gonna shake down
a cop in my district?
Well. it's not
a shakedown.
Take the card.
See the guy.
Or don't.
But then you're gonna
need a hell of a lot
more than a dentist.
You can leave it open.
How was work?
Well. same. you know.
Um. I have a trig
exam tomorrow.
can I go study?
Yeah.
I'll get it.
Hey. Come on in.
Meredith. this is Jason.
Bass player extraordinaire
and a very careful driver.
Hey. Lexi.
Hey.
Hi. Mrs. Olinsky.
Hi. Jason.
Nice to meet you.
I'll. uh. get
you a plate.